What did you eat for lunch today?
你今天午餐吃了什么？
Did you choose this dish because it was healthy, cheap or because it was just very tasty?
你选择这道菜是因为它健康、便宜，还是仅仅因为它非常美味？
Are you a fussy eater or an adventurous gourmet?
你是一个挑剔的食客，还是一个敢于尝试的美食家？
I love exploring trends in food.
我喜欢探索食物的趋势。
'Fusion cuisine' is not for everybody.
“融合菜肴”并不适合所有人。
My Italian grandmother would turn her nose up in disgust at the thought of tandoori pizza with mango topping but this marriage of tastes is perfectly fine in the 21st century.
我的意大利祖母一想到芒果配料的坦杜里披萨就会厌恶地皱起鼻子，但这种口味的结合在21世纪完全没问题。
Chef and food writer Ching-He Huang, who presented a series on Chinese Food for the BBC, is a fan of the movement.
厨师兼美食作家黄瀞亿（Ching-He Huang）是这一运动的粉丝，她曾为BBC主持了一系列关于中国美食的节目。
She says: "Fusion has been happening for centuries, for as long as people have travelled, but with the internet, and global travel, the exchange of ideas makes the process much faster."
她说：“融合菜已经存在了几个世纪，因为只要人们旅行，它就在发生。但随着互联网和全球旅行的发展，思想的交流使这一过程变得更快。”
Wolfgang Puck is seen by many as one of the chefs who made 'fusion' elegant.
沃尔夫冈·帕克（Wolfgang Puck）被许多人视为是使“融合菜”变得优雅的厨师之一。
He cut his teeth in his native Vienna and made a name for himself when he opened his own restaurant in Los Angeles in the 1970s.
他在家乡维也纳积累了经验，并在20世纪70年代在洛杉矶开设自己的餐厅时一举成名。
This European delved into Asian cuisine and became one of the first in a long line of celebrity chefs.
这位欧洲厨师深入研究了亚洲美食，并成为众多名厨中的先驱之一。
He said in an interview with the Wall Street Journal that initially he got negative responses from traditional American-Chinese restaurant owners but he is not bitter.
他在接受《华尔街日报》采访时表示，最初他得到了传统美式中餐馆老板的负面回应，但他并不感到不快。
"I believe authenticity is about evolution, not repeating your grandmother's recipe," he explains.
他解释说：“我相信本真是关于进化，而不是重复你祖母的食谱。
"Cooking is like painting or writing a song.
烹饪就像绘画或写歌。
Just as there are only so many notes or colours, there are only so many flavours – it's how you combine them that sets you apart."
正如音符或颜色有限，味道也是有限的——真正让你脱颖而出的是你如何组合它们。”
My granny's preference would be the Slow Food Movement.
我祖母更喜欢“慢食运动”。
Founded by her countryman Carlo Petrini in the 1980s and still going strong, it seeks to preserve regional cuisine and the use of ingredients that are grown locally.
该运动由她的同胞卡洛·佩特里尼（Carlo Petrini）于20世纪80年代创立，至今仍然蓬勃发展，旨在保护地方美食和使用本地种植的食材。
Petrini wants to see farmers connected more directly with consumers.
佩特里尼希望看到农民与消费者更直接地联系起来。
All these trends give us food for thought.
所有这些趋势都值得我们仔细思考。
We might be wasting an exciting opportunity to wake up our taste buds when we scoff a sandwich at our desks.
当我们在办公桌前狼吞虎咽地吃三明治时，可能浪费了一个唤醒味蕾的激动人心的机会。
Tomorrow, why not find an exotic restaurant and enjoy a feast?
明天，为什么不找一家异国风情的餐厅，享受一顿盛宴呢？
You dress trendy so eat trendy!
你穿得时髦，所以也要吃得时髦！